% of your plants and offices that were assessed 
(by entity or statutory authorities or third parties)
Child labour 100%
Forced/involuntary labour 100%
Sexual harassment 100%
Discrimination at workplace 100%
Wages 100%10. Assessments of the year
 All our locations on monthly basis submit Compliance Certificate which is documented in Legatix and compiled and 
presented to the board every quarter.
11. Provide details of any corrective actions taken or underway to address significant risks / concerns arising from 
the assessments at Question 10 above. 
 There were no significant risks / concerns arising from the above assessments.
1. Details of total energy consumption (in Joules or multiples) and energy intensity, in the following format: 
ParameterUnit of 
measurementFY2025
Current financial Year FY2024
Previous financial Year
From renewable sources
Total electricity consumption (A) GJ 114812 51268
Total fuel consumption (B) GJ 860147 454852
Energy consumption through other sources (C) GJ 0 0
Total energy consumed from renewable sources 
(A+B+C)GJ 974959 506120
From non-renewable sources
Total electricity consumption (D) GJ 366909 128000
Total fuel consumption (E) GJ 526691 657562
Energy consumption through other sources (F) GJ 0 0
Total energy consumed from non-renewable sources 
(D+E+F)GJ 893600 785562
Total energy consumed (A+B+C+D+E+F) GJ 1868559 1291682
Energy intensity per rupee of turnover  
(Total energy consumed / Revenue from operations)GJ/Cr. Rs. 106.06 124.74Businesses should respect and make efforts to protect and restore the environmentPrinciple
Essential Indicators
Note: We are consistently upgrading our data capturing mechanisms in order to make reliable and transparent Sustainability 
disclosures. Owing to this, we have revisited some of our previous recorded performance numbers to present more accurate 
position. Accordingly, we have revised the data points in water withdrawal for FY24 to reflect these modifications and accurately 
capture our conservation efforts. The figures for FY24 appearing in this report may be considered the most updated and accurate 
representation for the said year for TCPL India operation boundary.
29

 Note: Indicate if any independent assessment/ evaluation/assurance has been carried out by an external agency? (Y/N) If 
yes, name of the external agency
 Yes. The energy consumption data and energy intensity data are audited and verified by British Standards Institution (BSI) 
as part of æReasonable AssuranceÆ for the BRSR.
2. Does the entity have any sites / facilities identified as designated consumers (DCs) under the Performance, Achieve 
and Trade (PAT) Scheme of the Government of India? (Y/N) If yes, disclose whether targets set under the PAT 
scheme have been achieved. In case targets have not been achieved, provide the remedial action taken, if any.
 TCPL operates in a sector that does not fall under the classification of designated consumers (DCs), and as such, none of its 
sites are included in the Performance, Achieve, and Trade (PAT) scheme.ParameterUnit of 
measurementFY2025
Current financial Year FY2024
Previous financial Year
Energy intensity per rupee of turnover adjusted for 
Purchasing Power Parity (PPP) (Total energy consumed / 
Revenue from operations adjusted for PPP)GJ/million USD 219.12 130.05
Energy intensity in terms of physical output - Production GJ/MT 0.84 5.69
Energy intensity (optional) û the relevant metric may be 
selected by the entity- - -
3. Provide details of the following disclosures related to water, in the following format:
ParameterUnit of 
measurementFY2025  
Current financial Year FY2024 
Previous financial Year
Water withdrawal by source (in kiloliters)
(i) Surface water kL 2847221 2329406
(ii) Groundwater kL 320917 173115
(iii) Third party water (Municipal water supplies) kL 847479 178252
(iv) Seawater / desalinated water kL 0 0
(v) Others kL 0 0
Total volume of water withdrawal (i + ii + iii + iv + v) kL 4015617 2680773
Total volume of water consumption kL 6532755 4730690
Water intensity per rupee of turnover kL/Cr. Rs. 370.79 456.85
Water intensity per rupee of turnover adjusted for 
Purchasing Power Parity (PPP) kL/million USD 766.06 476.29
Water intensity in terms of physical output kL/MT 2.95 20.83
Water intensity (optional) û the relevant metric may be 
selected by the entity- - -
 Note: Indicate if any independent assessment/ evaluation/assurance has been carried out by an external agency? (Y/N) If 
yes, name of the external agency
 Yes. BSI Group India Pvt. Ltd has conducted an independent assurance.
30

ParameterFY2025  
Current financial Year FY2024 
Previous financial Year
Water discharge by destination and level of treatment (in kilo liters)
(i) To Surface water
 - No treatment 0 0
 - With treatment û please specify level of treatment 197 0
(ii) To Groundwater
 - No treatment 5632 0
 - With treatment û please specify level of treatment 0 0
(iii) To Seawater
 - No treatment 0 0
 - With treatment û please specify level of treatment 0 0
(iv) Sent to third parties
 - No treatment* 2356 24237
 - With treatment û please specify level of treatment 0 0
(v) Others
 - No treatment 30 0
 - With treatment û Tertiary treatment 24917 0
Total water discharged (in kilo liters) 33132 24237
 *Discharged to common Effluent Treatment Plant. 
 Note: Indicate if any independent assessment/ evaluation/assurance has been carried out by an external agency? (Y/N) If 
yes, name of the external agency
 Yes. BSI Group India Pvt. Ltd has conducted an independent assurance.
5. Has the entity implemented a mechanism for Zero Liquid Discharge? If yes, provide details of its coverage and 
implementation. 
 No. Some manufacturing units treat their wastewater internally using sewage treatment plants (STPs). This treated water 
is then recycled and used for landscaping and irrigation purposes.
6. Please provide details of air emissions (other than GHG emissions) by the entity, in the following format *: 
ParameterPlease specify 
unitFY2025
Current financial Year FY2024
Previous financial Year
NOx MT 418 73
SOx MT 34 7
Particulate matter (PM) MT 161 18
Persistent organic pollutants (POP) NA NA NA
Volatile organic compounds (VOC) NA NA NA
Hazardous air pollutants (HAP) NA NA NA
 Note: Indicate if any independent assessment/ evaluation/assurance has been carried out by an external agency? (Y/N) If 
yes, name of the external agency.
 Yes. BSI Group India Pvt. Ltd has conducted an independent assurance (æReasonable AssuranceÆ for the BRSR).4. Provide the following details related to water discharged:
31

Parameter UnitFY2025
Current financial Year FY2024
Previous financial Year
Total Scope 1 emissions* (Break-up of the GHG 
into CO2, CH4, N2O, HFCs, PFCs, SF6, NF3, if 
available)Metric tons of CO2 
equivalent64943 61501
Total Scope 2 emissions (Break-up of the GHG 
into CO2, CH4, N2O, HFCs, PFCs, SF6, NF3, if 
available)Metric tons of CO2 
equivalent71211 37282
Total Scope 1 and Scope 2 emissions Metric tons of CO2 
equivalent136154 98782
Total Scope 1 and Scope 2 emission intensity 
per rupee of turnover (Total Scope 1 and Scope 
2 GHG emissions / Revenue from operations)Metric tons of CO2 
equivalent/ Cr. Rs.7.73 9.54
Total Scope 1 and Scope 2 emission intensity 
per rupee of turnover adjusted for Purchasing 
Power Parity (PPP) (Total Scope 1 and Scope 
2 GHG emissions / Revenue from operations 
adjusted for PPP)Metric tons of CO2 
equivalent / 
million USD15.97 9.95
Total Scope 1 and Scope 2 emission intensity 
in terms of physical outputMetric tons of CO2 
equivalent/Metric ton 
of production0.06 0.43
 *Excluding refrigerants fillings, CO2 filling, STP emission.
 Note: Indicate if any independent assessment/ evaluation/assurance has been carried out by an external agency? (Y/N) If 
yes, name of the external agency.
 Yes. BSI Group India Pvt. Ltd has conducted an independent assurance.
8. Does the entity have any project related to reducing Green House Gas emission? If Yes, then provide details. 
 Yes, TCP has projects related to reducing Greenhouse Gas emissions, particularly through the utilization of alternate 
sources of energy.
 Our direct emissions come from various fuel sources, including biomass, diesel, petrol, furnace oil, coal, LPG, kerosene etc. 
used in operational processes. The indirect energy requirements are met through grid electricity, with a strong emphasis on 
leveraging solar power for off-grid configurations, which contributes to greening the energy portfolio. This year, 24% of the 
power demand was met through renewable sources, including wind and solar energy, further supporting the reduction of 
greenhouse gas emissions.
 The ICD Theni facility has successfully commissioned an additional 500 KWp solar power plant, complementing the existing 
1000 KWp plant. This enhancement brings the total solar capacity to 1.5 MWp, marking a significant step in the commitment 
to sustainable energy practices. Also, In FY 2024-25, we met 62% of its direct energy needs through bio-based fuels such as 
firewood, biomass pellets, spent tea waste, briquettes, and husk. This reflects a commitment to adopting energy solutions 
that are efficient and environmentally friendly.7. Provide details of greenhouse gas emissions (Scope 1 and Scope 2 emissions) & its intensity, in the following 
format: 
32

 These initiatives demonstrate our dedication to reducing greenhouse gas emissions and transitioning towards more 
sustainable energy solutions.
 For more information on the measures mentioned above, please refer to Annexure 5 of the Board's Report.
9. Provide details related to waste management by the entity, in the following format:
ParameterFY2025  
Current financial Year FY2024 
Previous financial Year
Total Waste generated (in metric tons)
Plastic waste (A) 6491 1139
E-waste (B) 1 65
Bio-medical waste (C) 143 11
Construction and demolition waste (D) 82 0
Battery waste (E) 10 3
Radioactive waste (F) 0 0
Other Hazardous waste (G)  û Used oil, used ink bottles, empty chemical 
containers, etc. 2248 790
Other Non-hazardous waste generated (H) û Metal scrap, bottom ash, etc. 15090 7193
Total (A+B + C + D + E + F + G + H) 24233 9203
Waste intensity per crore rupees of Turnover (Total waste generated / 
Revenue from operations in Cr. Rs.)1.38 0.89
Waste intensity per million USD of turnover adjusted for Purchasing 
Power Parity (PPP) (Total waste generated / Revenue from operations 
adjusted for PPP in million USD)2.84 0.93
Waste intensity in terms of physical output û Metric tons of waste/Metric 
ton of production0.01 0.04
Waste intensity (optional) û the relevant metric may be selected by the 
entity- -
For each category of waste generated, total waste recovered through recycling,  
re-using or other recovery operations (in metric tons)
Category of waste
(i) Recycled 21733 6875
(ii) Re-used 0 0.4
(iii) Other recovery operations 2248 2251
Total 23980 9126
For each category of waste generated, total waste disposed by nature of disposal method (in metric tons)
Category of waste*
(i) Incineration 143 3
(ii) Landfilling 110 77
(iii) Landfilling after incineration 0 0
Total 253 80
33

S. 
No.Location of operations/offices Type of operationsWhether the conditions of environmental approval 
/ clearance are being complied with? (Y/N) If no, the 
reasons thereof and corrective action taken, if any.
Not Applicable
S. 
No.Specify the law / regulation 
/ guidelines which was not 
complied withProvide details of 
the non-complianceAny fines / penalties / action taken 
by regulatory agencies such as 
pollution control boards or by courtsCorrective action  
taken, if any
Not ApplicableName and brief 
details of projectEIA Notification 
No.DateWhether conducted by 
independent external 
agency (Yes / No)Results communicated in 
public domain (Yes / No)Relevant  
Web link
Not Applicable10. Briefly describe the waste management practices adopted in your establishments. Describe the strategy adopted 
by your company to reduce usage of hazardous and toxic chemicals in your products and processes and the 
practices adopted to manage such wastes.
 At TCPL, we follow the 3Rs approachùreduce, reuse, and recycleùto manage waste effectively. Moreover, we have 
eliminated the use of hazardous and toxic chemicals in both our products and processes. Waste is carefully sorted according 
to legal requirements (domestic waste, hazardous waste, and industrial waste) and disposed of responsibly.
11. If the entity has operations/offices in/around ecologically sensitive areas (such as national parks, wildlife 
sanctuaries, biosphere reserves, wetlands, biodiversity hotspots, forests, coastal regulation zones etc.) where 
environmental approvals / clearances are required, please specify details in the following format: 
12. Details of environmental impact assessments of projects undertaken by the entity based on applicable laws, in 
the current financial year: 
13. Is the entity compliant with the applicable environmental law/ regulations/ guidelines in India; such as the Water 
(Prevention and Control of Pollution) Act, Air (Prevention and Control of Pollution) Act, Environment protection 
act and rules thereunder (Y/N). If not, provide details of all such non-compliances, in the following format: 
 Yes. The company is compliant with all the applicable laws.
34


